Zachary Scott Tarvit

Seeking a senior level role utilizing my understanding of UI/UX principles and my skills as a deep diving engineer. I strive for nothing less than excellence in both my products and my peers. 8+ years of professional experience, 18+ programming.

EXPERIENCE

Travel Syndication Technology, Alpharetta, GA— UI Engineer

November 2021 - Present

TST is the leading source of travel bookings from the AAA clubs in both USA and Canada (CAA). As their preferred vendor, our job is to cater to the needs of their consumers and booking sales agents. I have worked on the flight booking, hotel booking, and back-office support platform projects during my time here.

Environment: Javascript, Typescript, Scala, Jenkins, Drone, MySQL, Kubernetes, React, angularjs 1.x, Backbone, Twirl

Responsibilities:

- Operated in a pool of shared engineering resources that could be spun onto a different project at any time.
- Mentoring junior developers on industry best practices.
- Writing documentation for products covering onboarding, running procedures, and service troubleshooting guides.

Achievements:

- Improved map rendering performance for dense areas from being measured in seconds per frame on workstation computers to a locked 60FPS on mid-range phone hardware.
- Prevented several org-wide catastrophes when performing deep dives on build architecture.
- Integrated esbuild into the build process, cutting build times down from 17+ minutes, to ~40 seconds.
- Created an internal use component library for cross–product look and feel consistency.
- Worked with stakeholders to reduce scope of a project that was behind schedule in order to reaffirm core expectations and coordinate a smooth release.
- Migrated several pages to use modern technologies, for the purpose of reassigning ownership of changes to those pages from backend teams to the frontend team.

3326 Cameron Trail Peachtree Corners GA, 30092 (**508**) **579-0445**

zzzaaccckk@yahoo.com https://linkedin.com/in/zack-t/ https://github.com/TestSubject06

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA— Bachelor's in Computer Science

MAY 2015

Graduated with concentrations in Media and People, for skills in graphics / audio programming, HCI, and UI/UX

SKILLS

HTML / CSS / React / AngularJS /
Angular 2.0+ / SQL / Spring /
Velocity / JUnit / Karma / Enzyme /
ReactiveX / Git / Functional
Programming / Object Oriented
Programming / Lambda / EC2

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

C / C++ / C# / AS2 / AS3 / Haxe / Java JavaScript / TypeScript / Python

HOBBY PROJECTS

RetroPie Arcade Cabinet Power Supply Microcontroller (Arduino, Java, Soldering, Circuit Design)

Lobby Service & NAT Rendezvous (Node, UDP, Vercel, Planetscale)

Controller Input Visualizer for Twitch Streams (C++, SFML)

Pokemon G/S/C ROM Randomizer (Java, Reverse Engineering, Hex Editing Compiled Binaries)

Multiple entries into the Ludum Dare 48 hour game development competition (Haxe, OpenFL, Godot)

PREVIOUS EMPLOYMENT

Amazon AWS, Seattle, WA— Front-End Engineer

October 2019 - October 2021

As the sole front-end engineer in the EC2 Core Platform organization my role was equal parts requirements synthesis, and mentoring & teaching. I worked with customer service agents, org leadership, and other internal teams to facilitate ease of use for several internal tools related to EC2 capacity management.

Environment: Ruby, Javascript, Typescript, Java, React, EC2, Lambda, Jackson, Cypress, DynamoDB, Guice, Dagger Responsibilities:

- 24/7 OnCall rotation member handling global customer requests, and remediating service disruptions
- Org wide SME for a collection of internal tools, React, TypeScript, JavaScript, and end-to-end testing strategies
- Sharing front-end development best practices and knowledge to everyone working on interfaces in the local organization.
- Creating design wireframes to convey interactions to stakeholders
- Design reviews for front and back-end service components
- Code reviews for front-end components, including products outside of my direct ownership chain

Achievements:

- Successfully shepherded a product hand-off, moving ownership of a product and all of its related assets and users to another team
- Safely deprecated a decade old system by ensuring alternate tools were available to handle all use cases and fixing up those that weren't ready
- Spearheaded development on an internal tool responsible for managing temporary internal physical server requisitions
- Improved user experience of an existing user interface by improving both page optimization as well as accessibility and usability standards
- Brought a wealth of knowledge on both end-to-end and unit testing, resulting in a major increase in test coverage for several services
- Contributed to four internally facing user interfaces

Elavon, Sandy Springs, GA — Lead Front-End Engineer

June 2015 - October 2019

Headed front-end development on several internal and external sales tools, admin consoles, and various global customer interfaces with significant internationalization challenges. Worked closely with back-end architects to refine platform level designs.

Environment: Java, Spring, Hibernate, Velocity, Flyingsaucer(iText), RESTEasy, Jackson, JavaScript, TypeScript, AngularJS, React, JSP, JBOSS

Responsibilities:

- Working directly with product owners and business analysts to refine the requirements intake processes and refine story writing processes in such a way that junior devs could complete them
- Liaising both EU and NA requirements intake pipelines
- SME for AngularJS, Angular 2.0+, React, Redux, RxJS, TypeScript, JavaScript, Product Catalog, and localization processes
- Technical phone screens and panel interviews
- Training new developers on the front-end stack and best practices
- Headed development on 6 user interfaces, worked on at least 9

Achievements:

• Lead a team of 8+ UI developers to deliver a global product with over 90% Unit and Integration Test code coverage,

- in just 4 months
- Created a React application from the ground up servicing all self-service customers in the USA, Norway, UK, and Poland
 - Built a generic configuration-based layout engine to facilitate rapid development and deployment of changes
- Created an Admin Console framework using AngularJS for use in interfacing with users, code and equipment management, cache resets, quartz job recovery, and a ton of other touchpoints
 - Added role-based authentication to the Admin Console so that the Desktop Support team could log in and interact with user accounts, without seeing other internal system details
- Created a gulp build chain capable of producing any number of AngularJS project outputs while being able to share code between them freely
- Created a webpack build system that allows any number of build outputs for React projects while being able to tree-shake using TypeScript and share code freely between any of the projects
- Reduced page load times on the main internal sales tool from 3 minutes to less than 20 seconds
- Created a browser-based input recording tool for use in converting manual test cases into automated test cases, with batch patching

OTHER FUN TIMES

Dixie Air & Heat, Waycross, GA— Lead Software Engineer

Summer 2014

I developed a database and pricing system for an A/C installation company, as well as a front-end interface for sales agents to make quick sales decisions while on-site – plus administration tooling, and an automatic updater for when the devices came home. All from the ground up.

GaTech Outreach & Engagement, Atlanta, GA— Work Study

Fall 2014

The GaTech Outreach department was looking to repurpose some older laptops, so I suggested we use a lightweight linux distribution. The only thing that didn't make the transition was the LEGO NXT Mindstorm application, since that was windows only. So I wrote a visual coding editor in C# wrapped around a lib that used bluetooth to interface with the bricks.